Hello and welcome back.
In this module we're going to be creating a fun typing test project.
You can see that we have a very minimal UI here and we're using a cool mono space font.
You'll see why that is once we dive into the code.
And you can see at the bottom here we have 60 seconds on the clock.
So I'm going to go ahead and start typing and that is going to trigger the countdown.
So you'll see if I type the wrong letter it is red if I type the correct letter it is green.
I can backspace and try again and you'll see that eventually once I get to 20 characters
it will start scrolling to the side in order to reveal the rest of the words.
So we have 300 words in total so I'm going to think most people aren't going to get to 300 words
in 60 seconds here and I'm just going to fast forward through the rest of this.
Okay and you can see that the time is up and my final words for minute is 37.
So this is going to factor in any errors that I've made and that is going to reduce my score.
And if I go ahead and click try again you'll see that I have a whole new shuffled set of words.
Okay, very cool.
And if we inspect and we go to our mobile view and we refresh the page here.
You are going to see that this typing test is designed for desktop use only.
That is because it's a little bit difficult to consistently trigger the virtual keyboard
with how we have built this application.
So it is designed for desktop use only.
Okay, so without further ado let's dive into the code.
Oh and one quick note before we begin.
This course is actually part of a larger course called advanced CSS and JavaScript projects.
Where I walk you through step by step building five in-depth real world projects designed
to help you reach a top 10% level as a CSS developer.
So you might hear an occasional reference to a section or lesson from that full course
that doesn't fully apply here.
And don't worry, everything you need for this course is included and self-contained.
And if you enjoy what you learn here, I definitely recommend checking out the full advanced
CSS and JavaScript projects course next.
It's a great way to level up your front end skills with hands-on practical experience.
These projects are also the perfect thing for your developer portfolio.
All right, let's dive in.
(soft music)